JOSIAH BROWN

josiah.webdev@gmail.com | 682-239-6862 | Fort Worth, TX 76707

Portfolio Website

josiahbrown.com

Summary

Motivated React Developer with in-depth knowledge of JavaScript, ReactJS, HTML, and CSS. Experience writing code in multiple languages and building custom React web apps for clients. Known for always learning something new and a strong work ethic.

Skills

- ReactJS
- JavaScript
- HTML
- CSS, SCSS, Tailwind
- Python
- Command Line
- Bash Scripting
- WordPress

- Node.js
- Jest, React Testing Library
- C++, Java, Verilog (have not used in 1 year or more)
- Constant Learner
- Friendly and Outgoing
- Self-Directed
- Passionate About Diverse Cultures and Environments

Experience

9 06/2022 - 08/2022

Panther City Leather Fort Worth, TX

Full Stack Developer

- Panther City Leather Developed both back-end and front-end of panthercityleather.com
 - Completed code debugging and implemented fixes to resolve problems.
 - Began SEO optimization for client using Google Search Console.
 - View the completed site at panthercityleather.com

06/2021 - 05/2022

Volunteer

Free Burma Rangers Chiang Mai, Thailand

- Built and installed off-grid solar power systems.
- Chiang Mai, Thailand Developed custom software solutions to assist in trainings and office efficiency.
 - Created and edited videos describing human rights violations occurring in Myanmar.
 - Piloted a drone on the front lines of a war zone to obtain information regarding enemy position.
 - Passed 2 intense fitness tests required by the organization to be included on a mission.
 - Studied Thai and obtained an "Advanced Thai Language" certificate from Manna Thai Language School in less than 8 months.

05/2020 - 08/2020

Qorvo

Richardson, TX

Product Quality Engineering Intern

- Organized, archived, and created file management system for computer chips that had been previously tested by the product quality team.
- Analyzed data and technical documents to compose a list of parts to be converted to new epoxy
- Created and managed a database used by the PQE team to keep track of all tested products.

 Created a summarizing document and presented to the PQE team on the PQE standard stress tests.

05/2015 - 08/2019 Brown Woodworking Fort Worth, TX

Business Owner

- Designed, produced, and sold original woodworking projects (fountain pens, segmented vases, rocking chairs, dining tables, shutters, and 14' bookcases).
- Built projects observing ergonomics, end-user functionality, and long product life.
- Developed all marketing and sales functions. Kept track of all costs, set prices, photographed items, wrote product descriptions, managed packaging & shipping, and created a shop on Etsy.
- Interacted with customers frequently and developed a very high customer satisfaction rating. I never received less than a 5-star review.

Education and Training

05/2021 Waco, TX Bachelor of Science in Electrical and Computer Engineering

Baylor University

- 3.95 GPA
- Additional Coursework in Computer Science, Digital Logic Design, Electronic Design, Signals and Systems
- Summa Cum Laude

Languages

Thai:

Professional